AJIN: DEMI-HUMAN
Do you sleep well?
深く眠れるかい？
傷は癒やせたかい？
Did your wounds heal?
Just cos' they say the night is lonely
夜が寂しいからって
無理して
誰かを愛さないで
You don't have to force yourself
To love someone
They say I'm dreaming
夢を見る事だって
咽び泣く事だって
They say I'm sobbing
知りもしないまま
死んでみたって
They say I tried to die without knowing
Did you manage to hide?
上手に隠れたかい？
息は潜めたかい？
Did you hold your breath?
Just cos' they say it's tough now
You don't have to force yourself to change
今が苦しいからって
無理して自分変えないで
Even a brave savage
勇敢な蛮人だって
悩める子羊だって
Even a troubled lamb
回り道して生きているって
They are just wandering through life
So I don't stand out
目立たないように
堪えられるように
So I can put up with it
思考回路はまだ
止めないよに
So my train of thought won't stop yet
Tonight run away, run a way
It's unbelievable
今宵 RUN AWAY  RUN A WAY
嘘みたいだ
誰かこの手
掴んでくれよ
Someone take my hand
The tomorrow we can't see
Doesn't have to come
見えない明日は来なくていい
今はただ　眠りたい
Now I just want to sleep
HAVE YOU EVER SEEN A BLACK GHOST?
ゲームは好きかい？　田中君
Do you like games, Tanaka?
（田中）
ああ？
If you have 100 lives in a video game,
you can come back to life 100 times.
ゲームは100個の命があれば
100回生き返ることが出来る
しかし ゲームに裏技はつきもの
But all games have cheats.
もし 命を同時に
２個使ったとしたら…
What would happen if you were
to use two lives at once?
What happens to the extra life?
あぶれた命は どうなると思う？
そんなイメージだよ
Think of it like that.
Once you get the hang of it,
you'll be able to use it, too.
君もコツさえつかめば
扱えるようになる
Did you know...
（田中ＩＢＭ）
知ってるか？
亜人てのはな
大きな肉片を核に―
when an Ajin regenerates,
散らばった肉片を集めて
再生するんだ
any missing pieces meld back
with the largest piece?
But if a piece is too far away,
it's simply regrown.
だが 遠くに
行きすぎちまった肉片は―
回収されずに新しく作られる
（泉）
くっ…
What if that piece was your head?
（田中ＩＢＭ）
もし それが頭だったら…
ゾッとするだろ？
Gives you a chill, doesn't it?
Hey!
（田中ＩＢＭ）おい！
（泉）うっ…
（泉）あ…
（田中ＩＢＭ）何！？
What?!
You, too?
てめぇもかよ…
I wonder how long it's been
since I've brought out Kuro.
（泉）
クロちゃんを出すのは
いつぶりだろう？
（田中）
どうすんだ？　この場合…
What am I supposed to do now?
これ同士の戦い方は教わってねぇぞ
I wasn't taught how to fight
another one of these.
I've never fought one of these before.
（泉）
あれと戦った経験なんてない
どうすれば撃退出来る？
How do I defeat it?
Wait, is it even possible?
いや そもそも
撃退自体 可能なのか？
（田中）
これと俺をつないでるのは
たぶん頭だ
I'm probably linked to this thing
through the head.
（泉）
人の形をしている以上
狙うべきは…
Since it's shaped like a human,
I should aim for...
あっ… くっ…
（田中ＩＢＭ）へへ…
（田中）
再生… しただと？
It regenerated?
はぁっ… くっ…
What?!
（田中）
何！？　何だ？
再生しねぇじゃねぇか！
It's not regenerating?!
視界の伝達が…
My vision link...
My consciousness... is scattering.
意識が… 散る
こいつは… 粉砕！？　いや…
It's... pulverized. No.
（泉）
相殺？　打撃が有効！？
It damages both?
So, blunt attacks are effective.
（田中ＩＢＭ）
うっ…
I lost the link?!
途切れた！
Damn! So, the head really was
the weak point.
くそっ！
やっぱ頭が弱点だったか…
So, there's no point in slashing.
切っても意味なし
Blunt-force attacks are the only thing
that's effective.
効果があるのは打撃による粉砕か
フフ… 勉強になったぜ
Good to know.
はぁ…
I'll have to call in
the special team for this.
事後処理に特別班を呼ばなくては…
でも 戸崎さんが
いなかったのは幸い
But it's a good thing
Mr. Tosaki wasn't here.
And I was able to protect the girl.
それに あの子も守れた
あっ！　ああっ！？
くそっ！
Damn it!
That was just a diversion.
あいつは おとり…
もう１人いたのか！　くっ…
There was someone else!
This footage is from a month ago...
（戸崎）
この映像は１カ月前―
when Lab Number 2 was attacked.
第２研究室が
襲撃を受けた時のものです
So, this is the "variant power"
we've heard of.
（岸(きし)）
これが例の別種の力…？
Yes. The incident brought
the existence of variants to light.
（戸崎）
はい　この一件で別種の存在が発覚
We also learned the Shinya Nakamura
incident last year involved a variant.
去年の中村慎也(なかむら　しんや)事件も
別種が原因と分かりました
（コウマ）
ちょっと待て
“声”はどうなった？
Wait a second. What about the "voice"?
There's so much new information
popping up, I can't keep up.
新しい要素がポンポン出てきて
こっちは追いつかんよ
（若井(わかい)）
声については“擬死反射”
ということでケリがついてる
The voice has been explained
as causing a tonic immobility reaction.
"Tonic immobility"?
（コウマ）
擬死反射？
It's found in certain insects
as a defensive tactic.
昆虫などにも見られる防衛本能だ
In response to stimulus from
a stronger life-form, the muscles tense up
自分より優れた存在から
刺激を受けた際
筋肉が緊張状態となり―
and are unable to move for a time.
一時的に動けなくなることがある
Yes, but so far the voice hasn't been
a problem in any country.
（戸崎）
しかし 声は最初から
各国とも問題視していません
Since earplugs are sufficient protection.
（若井）
耳栓で十分防げるからね
（戸崎）
それに亜人と親しい人間や―
It's also reported
亜人を亜人と気づいていない
人間などに対しては―
to have a lessened effect on people
who know the particular Ajin well
効果が薄いという報告もあります
or people who don't know it's an Ajin.
今 考えるべきは…
What we should be--
（携帯の着信音）
-You should at least turn off your cell.
-Pardon me.
（太居(ふとい)）
電源ぐらい切っとくべきだろう？
すみません　重要な実験が
同時進行していまして…
We're currently carrying out
an important experiment as well.
（携帯の着信音）
SHIMOMURA
（田中）
はぁ…
（慧理子）
うっ うーん…
あっ！
What?! What is this? What's going on?!
何！？　何なの… 何なのよ！
兄さんの居場所なら知らないわよ！
I don't know where my brother is!
何か勘違いしているようだね
I'm sorry, I think you misunderstand us.
The truth is,
we just want to protect Kei Nagai.
私たちは永井(ながい)圭君を
守りたいだけだよ
Protect?
（慧理子）
守る？
…って 何から？
From--? From what?
From all sorts of things.
あらゆるものからだよ
The government, people after his bounty,
even foreign operatives.
政府や賞金目当ての連中
他国の工作員
I think you saw firsthand at the hospital,
君も さっき
病院で体験したと思うけど
危険な連中が圭君を狙ってる
there are dangerous people after Kei.
Who are you?
あなたは？
おお… 申し遅れたね
How rude of me.
AJIN REHABILITATION COMMITTEE
SATO
（慧理子）
あっ…
“亜人保護委員会 佐藤”…さん？
"Ajin Rehabilitation Committee."
Mr. Sato?
Kei is currently in
a very dangerous situation.
（佐藤）
圭君は今 非常に危険な立場に
立たされている
We want to find and rescue him.
私たちは彼を助けてやりたいんだ
兄さんと その…
So, then...
You'll save my brother
and the person helping him, too?
兄さんの協力者の人も
助けてくれますか？
Yes, of course, we will...
もちろんだとも
君が協力してくれればね
if you cooperate with us.
Okay.
分かりました
はぁ…
Well, I've been on death's door
for half a day.
まあ 半日死ぬような思いを
してきたわけだし―
幻覚を見ても不思議じゃないけど…
So, it's no surprise if I'm hallucinating.
頭は さえてるんだよな
Although, I'm thinking clearly now.
とりあえず これからどうするか
はっきりさせとこう
First thing, I need to decide
what I'm going to do next.
まず カイの言う九州行きは却下だ
これは はっきりしてる
Kai's idea of going to Kyushu won't work.
That's obvious.
この山から
一生 出ないという案は問題外
And staying on this mountain forever
is out of the question.
Which leaves me with one option:
contacting other Ajins.
残る手段としては
他の亜人との接触
If I can talk with them,
I should be able to learn something.
彼らと接触出来れば
何かしらの情報は得られる
But there are only two Ajins other than me
in the country.
ただ 国内の亜人は
僕の他に たった２人
And one of them is being held
by the government.
うち１人は
政府に捕まってるはず…
はっ！
Wait, no, there should be more.
いや もっといるだろう
According to the Ministry of Health,
Labor and Welfare,
厚生労働省の発表だと
日本の年間死亡者数は100万人以上
over a million people die
in Japan per year.
That means two people die every minute.
１分間に
２人死んでることになるんだぞ
So, there should be more Ajins in hiding.
いるはずだ　隠れてる亜人
彼らと接触すれば―
If I can get in contact, I can learn how
they live without being discovered.
人間にバレずに
生きていける方法が分かる
But the problem is how to contact them--
ただ 問題は どう連絡を…
（海斗）
圭…
Kei.
I'm back.
帰ったぞ
あ ああ… おかえり
Yeah. Welcome back.
はっ！
（海斗）
ん？　何だ？
What is it?
え？　あ いや…
Nothing.
（海斗）
とりあえず 夜まで休もう
Let's rest until nightfall.
We can switch off every hour.
１時間交代な
うん
Okay.
Oh, yeah.
（海斗）
あ いけねぇ
（カバンを開ける音）
Here.
ほれ
お… おう
（海斗のあくび）
Kai.
カイ ありがとう
Thanks.
（寝息）
あの…
So, are you really telling me the truth?
Will you help Kai?
ホントにカイさんのことも
助けてくれますか？
うん 約束するよ
You have my word.
（慧理子）
はぁ…
それで 兄さんがどんな人間か…
And you wanna know
what kind of person my brother is?
Yeah, just tell us anything
that comes to mind.
ああ 一応 聞いておきたいんだ
I'm not just saying this
because I found out my brother's an Ajin.
兄さんが亜人って分かったから
言うわけじゃないけど―
あの人を一言で言うなら…
If I had to describe him in one word...
You can't play with Kaito anymore.
（圭の母）
もう 海斗君と遊んじゃいけません
Why? You can't just tell me
without a reason.
（圭）
なんで？
理由がなくちゃ納得出来ないよ
（母のため息）
Okay, are you listening?
Kaito is the son of a criminal.
いい？　海斗君はね
犯罪者の子なの
Oh, well, in that case...
（圭）
だったら しかたないね
I was only hanging out with him
'cause he was always alone.
１人で可哀想だから
構ってやってただけだしね
My brother... is the worst.
兄さんは… クズよ
（佐藤）
フッ なかなか個性的な表現だ
That's a pretty bold statement.
Is there anything else you can remember?
他には何かあるかな？
Not really. That's about it.
別に… これといって…
（佐藤）
そうか　ありがとう
I see. Thanks.
では 君の役目は これで終わりだ
Well, then, that's all we need from you.
え… 何？
What?
えっ…
What are you...?
な… 何なの？
I need the Internet to find other Ajins.
他の亜人を探す手段はネット
そのためにも―
And for that, I need Kai's cell phone
since he hasn't been identified yet.
まだ身元がバレてない
カイの携帯が必要だった
But that's not the only reason
why I need it.
でも 携帯が必要な理由は
それだけじゃない
もう１つの道
それは他の亜人も―
There's another possibility.
Other Ajins might be searching for me.
僕を探そうとしているかも
しれないということ
If that's the case, they would do it
through a certain person.
となれば
いずれ しかるべき人物に到達する
（携帯のバイブレーター音）
ERIKO
そう 慧理子だ
Yes.
Eriko.
でも それは警察も同じ
But the same goes for the police.
慧理子が警察にカイのことを
話すとは思えないけど
I don't think Eriko would
tell the police about Kai,
but I need to make sure anyway.
それでも見極める必要はある
No one can take your call right now.
（留守電のアナウンス）
ただいま 電話に出られません
Please leave a message after the tone.
発信音の後にメッセージをどうぞ
（圭）
人間側か 亜人か
Humans or Ajins...
（佐藤）
君は 黒い幽霊を
見たことがあるかい？
Have you ever seen... a black ghost?
はっ！
This is Nagai.
永井です
ハハハッ
まさか 本人が出るとはね
I didn't think you'd answer yourself.
（圭）
あなたたちは亜人ですね
You're Ajins, right?
Indeed we are.
ああ いかにも
Why do you have my sister's phone?
なぜ 妹の携帯を？
To find out,
come to the place we tell you to.
（佐藤）
それが知りたければ―
こちらが指定する場所まで
来てほしい
Do you have transportation?
移動手段はあるかい？
ええ
Yeah.
There are probably two types
of Ajins living in secret.
隠れ住んでいる亜人は
大きく分けて２つのタイプだろう
A quiet type that keeps to himself,
and a dangerous type.
ひっそり過ごすタイプと―
もう１つは
物騒なことをするタイプ
And if that danger threatens
innocent people...
その物騒なことが―
及ぶべきでない人間にまで
及んだ時は…
If that happens...
その時は…
I'll kill them.
殺してやる
（セミの鳴き声）
あぁ…　はぁっ…
Damn, I may die of dehydration.
脱水症状で死ぬかも
でも これで死んだら―
But if I die, where does the sodium
and water I lost come back from?
失ったナトリウムと水分は
どこから来るんだろう？
あっ…
If this talk
with the other Ajins goes south,
もし 他の亜人と
話がこじれたら―
even if I can't be killed,
I could be captured instead.
殺される心配はないにせよ
監禁されるとか…
But that doesn't matter now.
でも 今の僕には
やつらに会う以外 道はない
I have no choice...
but to meet them.
What's with the outfit?
何だ その格好は
すみません
替えがなかったので…
I'm sorry,
I didn't have a change of clothes.
I tried to choose
the plainest clothes in--
お店でいちばん地味な物を
選んだつも…
Your report.
（戸崎）
報告を
はい　永井慧理子が
連れ去られたのが３時間前
Right. Eriko Nagai was taken
three hours ago.
"Tanaka" and "The Hat Guy" were the ones--
田中と帽子の仕業かと思われます
I don't care about that.
そんなことはどうでもいい
あっ…
I want to hear about how the battle
between the black ghosts went.
黒い幽霊同士の戦い
その過程と結果を知りたい
Yes, of course.
分かりました
（携帯の着信音）
（泉）まず…
-Well--
-Wait.
待て
This is Detective Araki.
（荒木(あらき)）
埼玉県警の荒木です
Eriko Nagai's cell phone has been used
just once after her abduction.
誘拐以降 永井慧理子の携帯が
１回だけ使われ―
The station figured out
the area it called from.
基地局から
通信エリアを割り出しました！
では その発信源を追ってください
Follow the source of that signal.
Whoever has their hands on that cell phone
seems to be trying to reach Kei Nagai.
その携帯の所持者は―
恐らく 永井圭と
接触しようとしているはず
（荒木）
あっ 了解しました
Understood.
静かで いい場所だろう？
It's a nice, quiet place, isn't it?
No visitors ever come,
and even the priest almost never shows up.
参拝客は 全然来ないし
神主も めったに顔を出さない
Mr. Sato and--
（圭）
佐藤さんと…
えっ！？
（刺す音）
（佐藤）うっ…
ん… ううん…
あれ？
Huh?
圭？
Kei?
はぁ…
He went off by himself.
あいつ １人で…
圭！
Kei!
うあっ！？
がっ ぐっ がはっ…
はぁっ…
ああっ…
Kai!
（慧理子）
カイさん
お兄ちゃん 来ないと思う…
I don't think my brother's coming.
Yeah.
（海斗）
ああ 電話あった
He called me.
（ため息）
Summer again, huh?
また 夏か…
（佐藤）
うーん…
ふぅ…
信じてもらうのに
いちばん手っ取り早いと思ってね
We figured this was the fastest way
to get you to believe us.
You're real.
（圭）
本物…
Should I do it, too?
僕もやりますか？
No, you don't need to.
You're already famous.
（佐藤）
いや いいよ　君は有名人だからね
彼も
So is he.
（圭）
あ！　田中か！？
Tanaka?! The second Ajin in the country.
国内２例目の亜人
There was nothing on the news,
did he actually break out?
ニュースでは
何も言ってなかったけど―
まさか脱獄したのか？
He looks dangerous.
物騒なやつ
（田中）
ああ？
けっ…
Well, then,
let's get straight to the point.
さて そろそろ本題に入ろう
電話で言ったとおり
我々は君を迎える準備が出来ている
Just as I said on the phone,
we're prepared to welcome you.
What you do now is up to you.
どうするかは 君しだいだ
Before I decide,
I have three questions to ask.
その前に
３つだけ質問させてください
Only three? Ask as many as you like.
（佐藤）
３つと言わず
好きなだけするといい
ふぅ… まず１つ目
慧理子をどうしたか
First question. What'd you do to Eriko?
We let her go.
（佐藤）
解放したよ
What?
はぁ？
え…　あれ？
What?
（救急隊員）
あっ もう 大丈夫ですよ
It's okay, miss.
We're almost at the hospital.
病院は すぐです
（佐藤）
今頃は病院に戻る途中だと思うが…
By now she should be on her way
back to the hospital, but...
I'm terribly sorry.
（佐藤）大変申し訳ない
（圭）え？
（佐藤）
言い訳にしか
聞こえないだろうが―
This must sound like an excuse, but...
this was the only way
we had to meet with you.
君と会うには
これしか方法がなかったんだ
妹さんにも
怖い思いをさせたに違いない
I'm sure we really frightened your sister.
ぶ… 無事ならいいんです
ちょっと心配だっただけなんで…
If she's okay, it's fine.
I was just a little worried.
Please, stop bowing.
頭を上げてください
I am really very sorry.
本当に申し訳ない
Anyway, please continue.
話を続けてくれ
（圭）
あっ… はい
Okay.
My second question...
２つ目の質問は
あなた方の日常について
is more about your daily life.
I want to know how you live.
How do you get by?
どうやって暮らしてるのか
それが知りたいです
I'm sure you must have been
treated terribly by many people
きっと君は
亜人と分かってから―
たくさんの人たちに
ひどいことをされたと思う
since you learned you were an Ajin.
（圭）
ええ… まぁ…
Yeah. Well...
But that's no reason
to hate all humans indiscriminately.
（佐藤）
しかし だからと言って―
人間をむやみに
敵視すべきではない
…と私は考えている
Or at least that's what I believe.
More human than human.
“人間より人間らしく”
これがモットー
That's our motto.
We live quietly. That's our daily life.
静かに暮らす
それが私たちの日常だよ
Although, he doesn't seem to approve much.
彼は あまり
納得していないようだがね
フン！
（佐藤）
永井君 君はどうしたい？
Now, then, what do you want to do, Nagai?
It's true, I have been treated terribly.
確かに ひどい目にも遭いました
There are definitely horrible humans
out there.
ロクでもない人間がいるのは
確かです
でも 佐藤さんと同じで―
But like you, Mr. Sato,
I don't see humans as enemies.
僕も人間を敵視するつもりは
ありません
（佐藤）
うん
All I want is to live a normal,
quiet life.
僕はただ 普通に
静かに暮らしたいだけです
フッ… フンッ
Nagai, I understand
your feelings perfectly.
永井君　君の考えはよく分かった
But, look, there's one thing
I want you to remember.
だがね これだけは
覚えておいてほしい
静かに暮らすのがモットーだと
私は言った
I told you our motto was to live quietly.
But if something awful
should happen to you,
だが もし 君が
理不尽な目に遭ったり―
捕まるようなことがあったら
話は別だ
or if you're captured,
then that's a different story.
If that should happen, I swear,
I will do whatever it takes to rescue you.
その時は最善の策を講じて
君を救い出すと誓う
Just like I rescued him.
彼を助けたように
Maybe...
（圭）
この人なら
信じていいのかもしれない
I can trust this person.
So, then, what's your final question?
それで？　３つ目の質問は？
（圭）
あ… すみません
Oh, sorry.
It's about this vision of a black ghost--
黒い幽霊の幻覚について…
（発射音）
はっ！
（田中）あっ…！
（佐藤）麻酔銃か！
-A tranquilizer gun!
-The police?!
け… 警察？
Get down, Nagai! We're under fire!
（佐藤）
伏せろ 永井君！
狙撃されている！
（刺さる音）
（圭）がっ！
Nagai! Stay with me, Nagai!
永井君！　しっかりしろ 永井君！
Mr. Sato... Run...
佐藤… さん…
逃げて…
Well, he didn't pass.
（佐藤）
不合格だな
（田中）
で どうするんです？
So, what do we do?
教育しなければねぇ…
We have to educate him.
TO BE CONTINUED
If my wish would come true
願い叶(かな)うなら
もう一度
Once again
I wanna touch your heart
君の心に
触れていたい
No matter how dark it gets
どんな闇でも
探してるんだ
I'll be searching
For my one
たったひとつの
光を
And only light
As I look up to the stars
Even though you are far
遠いけど
You're looking up at the same starry sky
同じ星空　見上げてる
In the sky of my heart
心の空には
雫(こぼ)れ落ちそうな
It's about to spill over
Your smile and
君の笑顔と
ぬくもり
Your warmth
Hear me
Until I went away and
Faced the lonely days
愛することの意味なんて
I thought I could understand
What it means to love
分かってたつもりだった
Feeling everything that
Was right in front of me
大切なもの失って
Losing something precious
Realizing real love
本当の愛に気付いて
I'll tell you now
I'll tell you now,
Just how close you are